# **EMILY KUANG**



#### **RESEARCH FOCUS**

My research explores the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Artificial Intelligence (AI), and User Experience (UX). I design, evaluate, and improve human-AI collaborative tools to support usability and UX analysis. I am a recipient of the 2023 Google PhD Fellowship in HCI.

I also collaborate with other researchers on topics including accessibility in computing education, and accessible technology for older adults and blind and low-vision people.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### PhD in Computing and Information Sciences

Aug 2020 - present

Rochester Institute of Technology, New York, United States Advised by Dr. Kristen Shinohara and Dr. Mingming Fan Participating in the AWARE-AI NSF Research Traineeship (NRT) Program

#### **BASc in Biomedical Engineering**

Sept 2015 - Apr 2020

University of Waterloo, Ontario, Canada Capstone advised by Dr. John Zelek Graduated on Dean's Honour List

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Rochester Institute of Technology**

Aug 2020 - present

Graduate Research Assistant

- Conduct HCI research on the human-centered design of AI-powered technologies, including visual analytics tools and conversational assistants to support UX analysis [C.3, J.3, C.6]
- Design, conduct, and analyze research studies employing a variety of methods including interviews, surveys, design probes, usability studies, and quantitative experiments
- Author technical papers for publication and develop dissemination plans

#### Meta, Reality Labs

May 2023 - Aug 2023

UX Research Intern

- Designed and led a 20-participant interview study on VR headset user experiences, efficiently collaborating with research vendors
- Actively contributed to project brainstorming workshops and internal product demos
- Effectively communicated findings to diverse product stakeholders, promoting a comprehensive understanding of user perspectives and needs

Last Updated: Oct 2023

Meta, Reality Labs

May 2022 - Aug 2022

UX Research Intern

• Conducted literature reviews and authored reports on first-hand experiences to inform the design of Ray-ban | Meta smartglasses

- Designed and conducted a user study with 30 participants to investigate audio performance
- Presented results to >100 product stakeholders including researchers, engineers, and cross-functional partners; recommendations led to changes in product design

#### Uncharted Software Inc., ASKE-E Team

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Research Intern

- Worked on the DARPA Automating Scientific Knowledge Extraction (ASKE) program
- Designed wireframes and implemented new features in the human-machine interface (HMI) of a visual analytics system for multi-scale graph analysis and knowledge discovery [W.1]

**Huawei Technologies Canada, Human-Machine Interaction (HMI) Lab**Jan 2019 - Aug 2020

Research Engineer

- Trained machine learning models for gesture recognition using Tensorflow
- Designed and conducted user experiments to explore novel interaction techniques on large screens using mid-air gesture input; presented at the Huawei Developer Conference 2019

## University of Waterloo, Vision and Image Processing (VIP) Lab

May 2016 - Apr 2018

Research Assistant

- Designed and 3D-printed a lens-free microscope [J.2] and a smartphone spectrometer [J.1]
- Conducted testing with biological specimens to achieve optical resolution in the nm range

#### PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

- C.7 Chutian Jiang, Wentao Lei, <u>Emily Kuang</u>, Teng Han, Mingming Fan. **Understanding Strategies and Challenges of Conducting Daily Data Analysis (DDA) Among Blind and Low-vision People.** Proc. ACM Conference on Computers and Accessibility (ASSETS), 2023.
- C.6 Emily Kuang, Ehsan Jahangirzadeh Soure, Mingming Fan, Jian Zhao, Kristen Shinohara.
  Collaboration with Conversational AI Assistants for UX Evaluation: Questions and How to Ask them (Voice vs. Text). Proc. ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2023. DOI: 10.1145/3544548.3581247
- C.5 <u>Emily Kuang</u>, Ruihuan Chen, Mingming Fan. **Enhancing Older Adults' Gesture Typing Experience Using the T9 Keyboard on Small Touchscreen Devices**. Proc. ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2023. DOI: 10.1145/3544548.3581105

- C.4 Xiaoying Wei, Yizheng Gu, Emily Kuang, Xian Wang, Beiyan Cao, Xiaofu Jin, Mingming Fan. Bridging the Generational Gap: Exploring How Virtual Reality Supports Remote Communication Between Grandparents and Grandchildren. Proc. ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2023. DOI: 10.1145/3544548.3581405
- C.3 <u>Emily Kuang</u>, Xiaofu Jin, Mingming Fan. "Merging Results Is No Easy Task": An International Survey Study of Collaborative Data Analysis Practices Among UX Practitioners. Proc. ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2022. DOI: 10.1145/3491102.3517647
- C.2 Xiaofu Jin, Emily Kuang, Mingming Fan. "Too old to bank digitally?": A Survey of Banking Practices and Challenges Among Older Adults in China. Proc. ACM Conference on Designing Interactive Systems (DIS), 2021. DOI: 10.1145/3461778.3462127
- C.1 Ameneh Boroomand, Mohammad Javad Sahfiee, Linda Wang, <u>Emily Kuang</u>, Farnoud Kazemzadeh, Alexander Wong. **Compensated lens-free light field spectroscopy**. Proc. International Conference on Inverse Problems in Engineering (ICIPE), 2017.

#### PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- J.3 Ehsan Jahangirzadeh Soure\*, Emily Kuang\*, Mingming Fan, Jian Zhao. CoUX: Collaborative Visual Analysis of Think-Aloud Usability Test Videos for Digital Interfaces. IEEE Transactions on Visualizations and Computer Graphics (TVCG), (Proc. of IEEE VIS), 2021. DOI: 10.1109/TVCG.2021.3114822 (\* denotes equal contribution)
- J.2 <u>Emily Kuang</u>, Farnoud Kazemzadeh, Alexander Wong. **Enhanced Smartphone Spectroscopy via High-throughput Computational Slit.** *Journal of Computational Vision and Imaging* Systems, vol. 2, no. 1, 2016. DOI: 10.15353/vsnl.v2i1.97
- J.1 Farnoud Kazemzadeh, <u>Emily Kuang</u>, Alexander Wong. **Compact, Field-Portable Lens-free**Microscope using Superresolution Spatio-Spectral Light-field Fusion. Journal of
  Computational Vision and Imaging Systems, vol. 2, no. 1, 2016. DOI: <u>10.15353/vsnl.v2i1.105</u>

#### PEER-REVIEWED EXTENDED ABSTRACTS & WORKSHOP PAPERS

- W.2 <u>Emily Kuang</u>. **Crafting Human-AI Collaborative Analysis for User Experience Evaluation.** In Extended Abstracts of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA '23). DOI: 10.1145/3544549.3577042 (In Press)
- W.1 Fahd Husain, Rosa Romero-Gómez, Emily Kuang, Dario Segura, Adamo Carolli, Lai Chung Liu, Manfred Cheung, Yohann Paris. A Multi-scale Visual Analytics Approach for Exploring Biomedical Knowledge. Proc. Workshop on Visual Analytics in Healthcare (VAHC), IEEE VIS, 2021. arXiv:2109.06828 [\*\*PBest Paper Winner]

## **INVITED TALKS & POSTERS**

•	Invited speaker for Youth Professional Career Development Series	10/2023
•	Invited speaker for RIT Computing and Information Sciences PhD Colloquium	09/2023
•	Guest lecture in ISTE266: Design For Accessibility	04/2023
•	Poster presentation at RIT Artificial Intelligence Summit	10/2022
•	Poster presentation at CRA-WP Grad Cohort for Women	04/2022
•	Guest lecture in ISTE782: Visual Analytics	11/2021

## **AWARDS AND HONORS**

Google Ph.D. Fellowship in Human-Computer Interaction ~ Google		
AWARE-AI NRT Seed Funding Award (\$1000 USD) ~RIT		
Department Nomination for Microsoft Research Ph.D. Fellowship $\sim RIT$		
Merit-based Ph.D. Scholarship ~ RIT	2020	
<b>Experience Award</b> ~ Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC)	2018	
President's Research Award ~ University of Waterloo		
President's Research Award ~ University of Waterloo		
<b>Undergraduate Student Research Award</b> ~ NSERC		
President's Scholarship of Distinction ~ University of Waterloo		

## **PROFESSIONAL SERVICE**

	• .	<b>~1</b> •	
Acco	CIATE	Chair	

• Chinese CHI 2023 Full papers

## Paper Reviewer

•	<b>ACM CHI</b> 2022, 2023, 2024	Full papers (Outstanding review recognition)
•	ACM CSCW 2023	Full papers
•	Frontiers in Computer Science 2023	Sec. Human-Media Interaction
•	Chinese CHI 2021	Late Breaking Work

#### **Student Volunteer**

<ul><li>ACM CHI 2022</li><li>IEEE VIS 2021</li></ul>	New Orleans, LA, USA Remote
Council Representative (2022-2023)	AWARE-AI NSF Research Traineeship
Project Judge (2022)	GENIUS Olympiad

Last Updated: Oct 2023

## ADDITIONAL PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### North Inc. (now acquired by Google)

Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

Computer Vision Developer

• Designed algorithm to quantify image sharpness for multi-camera system assembly

#### Synaptive Medical Inc.

Sept 2017- Dec 2017

Optics Engineering Intern

• Investigated the stabilization of stereoscopic videos for a neurosurgical robot

#### St. Michael's Hospital

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

Medical Imaging Research Assistant

• Worked on a video processing pipeline for non-invasive detection of diabetic foot ulcers

Last Updated: Oct 2023 5